<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>/2021/11/17/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/17/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>Clearly, many countries&#39; economies (or at least those we observed) are connected. We now know some explicit reasons why some of them are connected (like Australia and China, or proximity between Europe and Britain), but overall, I think it is better to see the ups and downs of markets as a global movement. Certainly, political factors, history, and government meddling aside, we are looking at indices, and what most affects the prices of indices (on the short term) are just people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Connections</title>
      <link>/2021/11/17/trade-connections/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/17/trade-connections/</guid>
      <description>So previously we talked about how there were correlations between index growth rates between countries. However, we were left with some discrepancies, namely the disproportionate and unexpected connections. I believe that at least some of this can be addressed through looking at how each country trades. Surely, if China traded way more with Australia in contrast with other countries, then their economies must be at least more related right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Correlations</title>
      <link>/2021/11/16/global-correlations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/16/global-correlations/</guid>
      <description>Now that we know that world economies are at least somewhat related, what can we do to measure the ‘relatedness’ and compare them? Well, we can use the growth rates in the previous post to calculate the correlation between two indices. The following map shows these correlations:
Now here it gets interesting. It should be quite obvious that countries would have more correlation based on their proximity, most obviously seen in the relatively bolder lines between China and Australia, and between Britain and Europe (although Europe isn’t a country).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth of Indices Over Time</title>
      <link>/2021/11/15/growth-of-indices-over-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/11/15/growth-of-indices-over-time/</guid>
      <description>In our modern-day global economy, we would expect economies to be interlinked. One great example of interlinked markets is how the Global Financial Crisis shocked not only the American economy, but also that of Australia’s, of Europe’s… In fact, the GFC affected the entire world’s economy.
Here, I would like to demonstrate a graph over time of major indices of five economies:- the Australian ASX 200- the Chinese CSI 300- the European SNP 350- the English FTSE 100- and the American SNP 500.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
